tips.net 2019-12-31

# Tips.Net: Privacy Policy (Tips.Net)

This privacy policy applies to all websites owned or operated by Sharon Parq Associates, Inc., including any Tips.Net site. (You can see a list of our websites by [visiting our main website](https://sharonparq.com/) and clicking on the "Our Sites" link near the top of the page.) **_This privacy policy was last updated 24 May 2018._**

## General Data Collection Policies

Sharon Parq Associates, Inc. is committed to protecting your privacy. We use the limited amount of information we collect to enable or enhance the functionality of our websites or to maintain you as a customer. These functions include allowing you to download information or purchase a product we may offer.

We collect information on our sites in two ways:

  * **Explicit collection:** Information you openly provide to us in order for us to help you better use our site, request information, sign up for newsletters, or purchase a product. This information is necessarily personally identifiable.
  * **Implicit collection:** Information collected by us automatically when you visit our site. This information is rarely personally identifiable.

We only explicitly collect personally identifiable information if absolutely necessary (for instance, to complete a purchase you have initiated). It is our strict policy that personally identifiable information—such as your name, postal address, e-mail address, or telephone number—is private and confidential. Accordingly, the information you may provide is stored in a secure location, is accessible only by designated staff, and is used only for the purposes for which you provide the information.

## Implicit Collection: Information We Collect Automatically

We automatically collect specific information about your use of our sites. This information may include unique device identifiers, IP addresses, browser characteristics, operating system details, referring URLs, length of visits, and pages viewed. We may use tools such as cookies, embedded scripts, web server logs, or other similar technologies to collect details about the services and devices you use to access the information on our sites.

  * **Cookies:** A cookie is a unique identifier that is stored on a visitor's computer or device. Cookies may be used for various purposes, including to track user preferences such as whether a newsletter subscription invitation has been previously displayed to the visitor.
  * **Embedded Scripts:** An embedded script is programming code designed to collect information about a user's interactions with a website. Typically, the script is temporarily downloaded onto a visitor's computer from our server or the server of a third-party service provider and is active only while the visitor is connected to the site, then deleted or deactivated after the site is exited.

Implicit information may be automatically collected by third-parties we rely upon to help us accomplish our business purposes. The names of our third-party partners may change from time to time, as our business needs change. Contact information for the third parties we use is available upon request to allen (at) sharonparq.com.

## Data Analytics

Our sites may use third-party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics, to help us analyze how visitors use our sites. These services track information about visitors including IP addresses, browser types, referring pages, pages visited, and time spent on particular pages. We use this information to improve our products and tailor the user experience on our sites. To learn more about how Google may use information collected through our sites, [click here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). For information on how to opt out of data collection through Google Analytics, [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

Your web browser may have settings that allow you to transmit a "Do Not Track" signal when you visit various websites or use online services. Like many websites, ours are not designed to respond to "do Not Track" signals received from browsers. To learn more about "Do No Track" signals you may want to [visit this site](https://allaboutdnt.com/).

## How We Share Your Information

In most cases we don't share your information. Period.

It is our strict policy to never sell, rent, or give away any personally identifiable information about you to any third-party whose use of that data would extend beyond our business purposes. For instance, if you order a product from us, your payment information may be verified with a financial institution and your e-mail or postal address will be used to send you the product.

We will not share our newsletter subscription lists with others, period. We will not sell, distribute, post, copy, or otherwise disseminate your subscription e-mail address or other personal information to others.

We will release your personal information if required in a judicial or governmental investigation or proceeding.

## Security

We maintain physical, electronic, and administrative safeguards designed to protect personal information that we obtain in accordance with this policy. Although we use reasonable efforts to secure such information, transmission via the Internet is not entirely secure, and we cannot guarantee the confidentiality of information transmitted to us over the Internet.

## Links to Other Websites

Our sites may contain hyperlinks to other websites or online locations for your convenience and information. Those linked websites may have their own privacy policies or notices and may be operated by unaffiliated entities. This policy does not apply to websites we do not own or control, so please review the privacy policies posted on those sites to understand how they may collect and use your personal information. We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of websites we do not control.

For a list of websites owned and operated by Sharon Parq Associates, [visit our main website](https://sharonparq.com/) and click on the "Our Sites" link near the top of the page.

## Information for Users Outside the United States

Sharon Parq Associates, Inc., is located in the United States, and U.S. laws govern the information we collect. If you are visiting our sites from outside the United States, please be aware that information we collect (either explicitly or implicitly) will be transferred to and processed in the United States. By using our sites, you acknowledge and consent to the transfer and processing of your personal data in the United States as described in this policy. The data protection laws and regulations applicable to your personal data transferred to the United States may be different from the laws in your country of residence.

## Your Data-Related Options

If at any time you would like to add or remove your name from any of our subscription lists, correct your information, or question how any information is used (whether explicitly provided or implicitly collected), you can send a personal e-mail to allen (at) sharonparq.com. To help protect your privacy and security, we may take reasonable steps to verify your identity before honoring any such requests.

Many web browsers provide options to allow you to stop accepting new cookies or to disable existing cookies. Go to the Help function of your browser to learn how. You can also go to [AboutCookies.org](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) for information about how to disable and control cookies on most browsers. Please be aware that if you disable the cookies on your computer, you may not be able to use specific features of our sites or other websites.

You may unsubscribe from receiving promotional e-mails from us by following the instructions provided in those e-mail communications. (Look at the very end of any newsletter or e-mail you receive to see the appropriate links.) Please note that even if you opt out of receiving promotional communications from us, we may continue to send you non-promotional e-mails such as e-mails concerning our ongoing business relationship with you.

## Contact Us

To contact us regarding our privacy policy, our privacy practices, or your options, e-mail us at allen [at] sharonparq.com or send postal mail to:

Sharon Parq Associates, Inc.  
Attn: Allen Wyatt  
PO Box 1187  
Mountain View, WY 82939
